<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-01-25T10:17:07-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Hiatt Zhao</title><subtitle>Portfolio
</subtitle><author><name>Hiatt Zhao</name></author><entry><title type="html">Week 2: Revise Goals</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/25/week-2-revise-goals.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 2: Revise Goals" /><published>2020-01-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/25/week-2-revise-goals</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/25/week-2-revise-goals.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been a week since I started my first &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/01/18/30-by-7-project.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;#30by7project&lt;/a&gt;. There are some things I learned about my behavior and my habits that I think are helpful in revising my goals for the next several #30by7projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned that I get really tired after I come home and eat dinner. I think it’s the result of both work and food coma. It’s not ideal for me to do things that require a lot of focus. Thus, I tend to do more creative tasks in the early evenings, such as writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though my first week’s goal was to make a YouTube video every day, it didn’t work as planned. I recorded several, but only found one that’s decent enough to upload. What I did next was to switch to a goal of playing the guitar every day for a week. As of this Saturday morning, I’ve played the guitar three times this week for at least half an hour each. Three out of 7 is a failing grade in my book, but to see a more complete picture, I’ve read chapters in two books 5 days out of the 7 and have written something 4 days out of 7. I didn’t have a #30by7project goal of reading and writing initially, but I included them because I do them outside of work and they will improve myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks like the best strategy for me to complete my #30by7project goals is to do multiple #30by7projects simultaneously. If I complete three goals in three weeks, that’s an average of one goal per week. If some goals become habits, such as reading and writing, then I will continue to do them as long as they provide enjoyment and value. I think that’s the ultimate goal of doing a #30by7project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hiatt Zhao</name></author><summary type="html">It’s been a week since I started my first #30by7project. There are some things I learned about my behavior and my habits that I think are helpful in revising my goals for the next several #30by7projects.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">#30by7project</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/18/30-by-7-project.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="#30by7project" /><published>2020-01-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/18/30-by-7-project</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/18/30-by-7-project.html">&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, I tried to do a #30DaysOfCode to get better at web development. It’s a self imposed challenge where I would practice coding for 30 days straight. I didn’t complete that challenge and I think I only finished half way. Recently, I thought about what I did wrong and what I should change if I were to do something like that again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I think 30 days is too long for me. To me a week is a good start so that I can gauge myself and see if I like the challenge to begin with. Seven days is not a huge time investment and I would only be a beginner at whatever I’ll be doing. And that’s fine with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, with the #30DaysOfCode challenge, it doesn’t specify how long I should code per day. Again, just to start, I think a 30 minute learning session is best for me since I do have a full-time job on the weekdays. If I choose to do more than 30 minutes then that’s great, but the minimum threshold is 30 minutes per day. I think that’s very doable for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, with #30DaysOfCode, it was with coding only and it was very popular on social media where people publicized their challenges. Though I did see others modifying the challenge to do 30 days of design, etc. I want to do a 30 minutes by 7 days challenge for anything that I might be interested in. This includes learning the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;React&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Angular&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Node&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flutter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data science&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SQL server&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Java&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Command line&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Machine learning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drawing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Guitar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I learn each of these for 30 minutes a day for 7 days straight I’ll have a good introduction to each of these topics. If I want to continue learning the same topic then I’ll just do another 7 day challenge of the same subject matter. No pressure to complete a straight #30DaysOf challenge. I call my learning challenge the #30by7project. Foe example, if I start with learning React for 30 minutes a day for 7 days, it’ll be #30by7react challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting tomorrow, I’ll start with my first challenge. Let’s see how it goes now that I’ve set the bar low.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hiatt Zhao</name></author><summary type="html">Two years ago, I tried to do a #30DaysOfCode to get better at web development. It’s a self imposed challenge where I would practice coding for 30 days straight. I didn’t complete that challenge and I think I only finished half way. Recently, I thought about what I did wrong and what I should change if I were to do something like that again.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Christmas List</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/12/christmas-list.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Christmas List" /><published>2019-12-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/12/12/christmas-list</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/12/christmas-list.html">&lt;p&gt;I still remember my first Christmas in 1995 when I arrived in the US. I received so many presents, mostly toys, that I felt like I was in heaven. It seems like as I get older each year I want fewer and fewer things for Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very grateful for what I have. A place to live, a reliable car, a great family, great friends, easy access to several great grocery stores, enough clothes to wear, a computer and internet, a great job, a nice bicycle in case I need to exercise, and most importantly, good health. I simply don’t need anything else. In fact, I should be getting rid of some things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for Christmas this year, my list is bare. But that doesn’t mean it’s empty. If you would like to gift me something, I suggest donate to your favorite charity. One of my favorite charities is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.givedirectly.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GiveDirectly&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a well ranked non-profit organization that gives money directly to the poor. Since income inequality is something that I feel strongly against, I feel this organization does a great job to help the needy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope I don’t sound selfish to say that I don’t want anything for Christmas. However, I feel as a member of the society, I’m in a good place and there are others who need more help than me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hiatt Zhao</name></author><summary type="html">I still remember my first Christmas in 1995 when I arrived in the US. I received so many presents, mostly toys, that I felt like I was in heaven. It seems like as I get older each year I want fewer and fewer things for Christmas.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Man?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/07/man.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Man?" /><published>2019-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/12/07/man</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/07/man.html">&lt;p&gt;I started this piece by randomly making marks with lines until I realized that what I was drawing was a profile of a person. I don’t know if it’s a man or a woman. I don’t think it really matters. Might as well be a banana duct taped to a wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog_pics/2019_12_07-man.png&quot; alt=&quot;Man?&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Hiatt Zhao</name></author><summary type="html">I started this piece by randomly making marks with lines until I realized that what I was drawing was a profile of a person. I don’t know if it’s a man or a woman. I don’t think it really matters. Might as well be a banana duct taped to a wall.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Festival</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/03/the-festival.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Festival" /><published>2019-12-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/12/03/the-festival</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/03/the-festival.html">&lt;p&gt;I want to start drawing again and rediscover my creative side. I want to apply the same approach as I did with writing. No judgments, just draw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog_pics/2019_12_03-festival.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Festival&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Hiatt Zhao</name></author><summary type="html">I want to start drawing again and rediscover my creative side. I want to apply the same approach as I did with writing. No judgments, just draw.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Night</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/02/the-night.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Night" /><published>2019-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/12/02/the-night</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/02/the-night.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been staring at the computer screen for about 15 minutes trying to think of what to write for my first post on this website. Nothing and everything comes to mind. I think it’s what people call all-or-nothing thinking. I’m good at that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking comes naturally to me. Some people, such as my mom, tell me that I think too much, but I think people are always thinking. I’ve only been thinking for the past 35 years. There are plenty of people who have thought twice as much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess what I’m trying to do is to transcribe something in a vacuum - my mind - to something visual - words - so that you can peak inside my head. I don’t know why you would want to step into someone else’s head, but it’s something we tend to do. Like watching a TV show or reading a book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do have to say that I’m an interesting person. Though, my mom once told me that I’m very boring. I might not be the most interesting, but interesting enough. And I want to expand my interest by writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started keeping a private journal about 10 years ago. I tried to write a public blog a few times, but I always let time get the best of me. For some reason, I kept writing on the journal. I think it’s because I feel there’s no pressure for anyone to criticize me. As a result, there’s no limit to my writing, no matter how bad it is, I’m the only judge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To test this hypothesis, I’m going to do the same on this blog. Just write whatever and see what comes out of it. It’s my hope that something of value will result, either for you or me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog_pics/2019_12_02-window.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;window&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Hiatt Zhao</name></author><summary type="html">I’ve been staring at the computer screen for about 15 minutes trying to think of what to write for my first post on this website. Nothing and everything comes to mind. I think it’s what people call all-or-nothing thinking. I’m good at that.</summary></entry></feed>