<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-12T11:12:35-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Hiatt Zhao</title><subtitle></subtitle><author><name>Hiatt Zhao</name></author><entry><title type="html">What is Success? According to Me.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/12/what-is-success.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Success? According to Me." /><published>2020-07-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/12/what-is-success</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/12/what-is-success.html">&lt;p&gt;When I was in high school, I thought success was getting the best grades so I can attend a good college. When I was in college, I thought success was getting the best grades so I can go to medical school or graduate school. I didn’t go to medical school after all and I only ended up going to graduate school 8 years after I graduated from college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one has ever told me that &lt;strong&gt;success is not what other people dictate to you, but it’s something you have to define on your own&lt;/strong&gt;. My teachers and guidance counselor certainly didn’t teach me this. Maybe it was my fault for not asking. It wasn’t until later that &lt;strong&gt;I realized what really gets taught in schools: a skill, so you can serve in the working force&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schools don’t want you to be financially independent. That’s why financial acumen isn’t taught. In high school, I was taught mathematics, English, biology, chemistry, physics, French, history, and gym. For God’s sake, why is gym even a class I still don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teachers expect you to be a good citizen by working in a career, contributing something to society. This is the hidden agenda that most people are used to. And society wants you to be a cog in a machine and doesn’t want you to be an outlier. And &lt;strong&gt;schools want to churn out as many cogs as they can for this machine&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I discovered most of my life was wasted on things I shouldn’t have cared too much about, such as good grades. &lt;strong&gt;I should focus on what I really want to do: experience life, work less, travel more, take care of the earth, meet people, take in new ideas.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was freed after finishing my formal education, but the real education begins and continues; because &lt;strong&gt;life is about learning, adapting, changing, testing, and then the cycle continues again until you reach greater wisdom&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all is not lost. I was taught English by my teachers, and because of them I can read and write. I was taught science, and because of that I can think scientifically and logically. &lt;strong&gt;I can regret certain things in my life, but it’s more useful if I’m grateful for the things I have learned and use them to gain new insights.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As to what success really is, I once asked a professor in graduate school. He replied that success is having a goal and reaching it or surpassing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I believe success is an illusion, and so is failure.&lt;/strong&gt; In fact, there shouldn’t be a separation between success and failure because one can’t live without the other. To have success, it means you have tried, and to have tried means you must had some failures, to even have the courage to try again means that you succeeded in overcoming your previous failures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The more important thing is to do.&lt;/strong&gt; Do something so that you can be better, whether that be a new skill or something else. Even if you end up not liking the things you’ve done, at least you learned something about yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Success is built cumulatively and is an evolution.&lt;/strong&gt; What I thought was lacking in schools I learned later due to my curiosity. And what I will learn in the future depends on my current state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So make the choice today to have a positive change. And when today is over, be grateful for everything that has happened. When tomorrow comes, begin anew.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hiatt Zhao</name></author><summary type="html">When I was in high school, I thought success was getting the best grades so I can attend a good college. When I was in college, I thought success was getting the best grades so I can go to medical school or graduate school. I didn’t go to medical school after all and I only ended up going to graduate school 8 years after I graduated from college.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Manifesto</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/08/manifesto.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Manifesto" /><published>2020-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/08/manifesto</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/08/manifesto.html">&lt;p&gt;I am an explorer of life, both in the physical space and in the mental realm. I seek riches. They are memories, experiences, talents, knowledge, and wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To achieve these things I need to learn, travel, and experience as much as I can in life. Thus, I grant myself to make mistakes and to celebrate my wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also know that my emotions are subjective, so enjoying every single moment is the key to a beautiful life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must do what I love and do them often. I must share with the world with what I have. And I must help others when I can. Because I want to leave a better world than the one I arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that I’m capable of much more than I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And do good. Always.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*This was written in 2016. Not a single word has been changed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hiatt Zhao</name></author><summary type="html">I am an explorer of life, both in the physical space and in the mental realm. I seek riches. They are memories, experiences, talents, knowledge, and wisdom.</summary></entry></feed>