<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-12-02T22:13:57-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Hiatt Zhao</title><subtitle>Portfolio
</subtitle><author><name>Hiatt Zhao</name></author><entry><title type="html">The Night</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/02/the-night.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Night" /><published>2019-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/12/02/the-night</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/02/the-night.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been staring at the computer screen for about 15 minutes trying to think of what to write for my first post on this website. Nothing and everything comes to mind. I think it’s what people call all-or-nothing thinking. I’m good at that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking comes naturally to me. Some people, such as my mom, tell me that I think too much, but I think people are always thinking. I’ve only been thinking for the past 35 years. There are plenty of people who have thought twice as much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess what I’m trying to do is to transcribe something in a vacuum - my mind - to something visual - words - so that you can peak inside my head. I don’t know why you would want to step into someone else’s head, but it’s something we tend to do. Like watching a TV show or reading a book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do have to say that I’m an interesting person. Though, my mom once told me that I’m very boring. I might not be the most interesting, but interesting enough. And I want to expand my interest by writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started keeping a private journal about 10 years ago. I tried to write a public blog a few times, but I always let time get the best of me. For some reason, I kept writing on the journal. I think it’s because I feel there’s no pressure for anyone to criticize me. As a result, there’s no limit to my writing, no matter how bad it is, I’m the only judge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To test out this hypothesis, I’m going to the same on this blog. Just write whatever and see what comes out of it. It’s my hope that something of value will result, either for you or me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog_pics/2019_12_02-window.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Window&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hiatt Zhao</name></author><summary type="html">I’ve been staring at the computer screen for about 15 minutes trying to think of what to write for my first post on this website. Nothing and everything comes to mind. I think it’s what people call all-or-nothing thinking. I’m good at that.</summary></entry></feed>